# PHILIP DUSHIE, PGCert, BSc.

Full Stack Developer

philip.dushie@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/pdushie https://philip.lovestoblog.com 782-882-7489

Herring Cove Road, Halifax, NS, B3R 1W9, Canada

Dedicated IT professional with over five years of experience in systems administration, technical support, and full stack application development. Skilled at designing and building highly responsive websites and web applications.

# **Core Skills**

Web Design: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Database Administration: MySQL,

PostgreSQL, MSSQL,

 $Network\ Administration:\ LANs,\ VLANs,$ 

WLAN,

Network Security: Firewalls, Network

Monitoring, Data Protection,

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows,

MacOS,

Virtualization: VMWare, Hyper-V, VirtualBox,

Office 365,

Technical Troubleshooting: Hardware,

software,

Project Management: Project Planning,

executing, managing IT projects,

Software & Hardware: Installation,

configuration, maintenance,

Training: IT System training,

Teamwork, Time Management

## **Education**

## **Nova Scotia Community College**

Sep 2023 - May 2024

**Graduate Certificate** 

IT Programming for Artificial Intelligence

# Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology

Jun 2010

**Bachelor of Science** 

Computer Engineering

#### Languages

English (Proficient)

# **Work Experience**

#### **Systems Administrator Intern**

Apr 2024 - May 2024

Online Job Market | Halifax

- Provided comprehensive technical support and assistance, ensuring optimal operation of the organization's web services.
- Successfully migrated Online Job Market's web platform from Apache to Nginx with 99.8% uptime.
- Implemented security strategies to harden and secure web infrastructure.
- Installed, configured, and maintained desktop hardware and software applications for over 100 users.
- Automated tasks for software updates and backups to ensure business solutions and systems were current and secure.

# **IT Systems Administrator**

Dec 2014 - Aug 2023

Nursing and Midwifery Council Of Ghana | Accra

- Delivered customer service-focused technical support to over 200 employees in a fast-paced dynamic work environment.
- Installed, configured, and updated desktops, laptops, peripherals, and software applications.
- Conducted troubleshooting and diagnosis of hardware and software problems, ensuring timely resolution of user problems.
- Documented support activities and solutions for future reference.
- Participated in on-call rotations for after-hours support.

# **Projects**

# Responsive Website Design for Acme Adventure Travel

Oct 2024 - Oct

2024

Designed and built a responsive and mobile friendly website for Acme Adventure Travel. Design was done purely with HTML and CSS from the scratch.

- Developed a website for Acme Adventure Travel using HTML/CSS.
- Website was designed to be highly responsive and mobile friendly.
- Successfully configured Apache web server on Amazon web services to host the website.
- To ensure data protection, SSL certificate was applied to the website.

# **Certificates**

# **Cisco Certified Network Associate** (CCNA)

Cisco

## **IPTL Certified Engineer**

IP Technology Labs, USA

## **Nova Scotia Class 5 Drivers License**

# **Air Quality Index Prediction App**

Apr 2024 - Apr 2024

Designed and built an app to predict the air quality index using decision tree regression.

- Developed an HTML/CSS front-end to receive user inputs and pass them to the backend to predict the AQI.
- Developed a Flask backend that provided API endpoints to receive inputs.
- The model was a Decision Tree Regression model trained on US air pollution data from the year 2000 to 2016.
- Achieved 98% prediction accuracy on test data and 94% on training data in predicting Air Quality Index.

#### **LLM Optimization**

Apr 2024 - May 2024

Fine tuned the Llama 2-7b model to become an expert in job search and interview skills.

- Built and fine-tuned the Llama 2 model using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG).
- he model was optimized to be able to provide guidelines in the fields of job searching and interviewing.
- Successfully deployed the model to the Google Colab cloud platform and made it publicly accessible.